There's a new way to see inside your
body that could replace MRIs, and it
only uses water and sound. So, your
typical MRI machine uses magnets and
radio waves to move protons in your
body, creating signals that the machine
converts into images, which is amazing.
But, to use this machine, you have to
step into [music] a water bath, and then
you're slowly lowered down at about 5 cm
per second. And around you is a ring
with these tiny little sensors, each one
about the size of a grain of sand, that
act as a speaker and a microphone,
creating tiny vibrations that build up
into one fast sound wave that travels
across the tank in 1/2000 of a second.
And as the wave [music] passes through
your body, it changes shape depending on
what it's going through. The sensors in
the ring go one by one until they've
encompassed your whole body, capturing a
whopping 17 GB of data per second. So,
by looking at how each [music] wave
changes shape, they can create an image
of what a slice of your insides looks
like. And it does this again and again
and again as you're slowly lowered
through the ring, [music] imaging
several hundred slices of your body in
only 60 seconds, nearly 100 times faster
than an MRI, which could mean more
people could more easily get them.
They're still testing this, but see when
you can use it. Subscribe.